Guide to the Ruth Asawa Papers M1585
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 12. Student Art and Correspondence
  - 12.5 Everett Junior High School Alvarado Arts Workshop project, 1974-1976 (Box 158, Folder 5, Box 159, Folder 1)
    Project led by Merry Renk, Marion Norberg, and Annette Clark. Includes photographs and captions [removed from photo album], student report, Renk draft report, and other writing.
  - 12.6 student publications and project documentation
    Poetry, art, photographs and other work, much of which appears in magazine or scrapbook format. Many are connected with Alvarado Arts Workshop. Some appear self-produced, others were made by teachers or workshop coordinators.
    see also student publications in School of the Arts series.
    - 1970-1973 (Box 159, Folder 2)
      unknown school Valentine’s Day 1970; James Lick "Skipper’s Log" Spring 1971; McKinley (Redwood City) 1972; Mission High School "West Wing" circa 1973 (with Asawa interview).
    - "…and the sun is still shining" (Mission High School PACE project), 1972 (Box 159, Folder 3)
    - Boathouse Mural project (Winfield Scott, Jedediah Smith), 1974 (Box 159, Folder 4)
      Alvarado project organized by Asawa.Contains photographs by Laurence Cuneo.
    - 1975-1976 (Box 159, Folder 5)
      Documents Alvarado Arts Workshop projects at Commodore Stockton, Jefferson, and St. Philip.
    - Teaching Poetry to Kids (Dudley Stone, Daniel Webster), 1976 (Box 159, Folder 6)
    - AAW Chinese Puppet Theatre Report, 1977-1978 (Box 159, Folder 7)
    - Facets, 1977-1978 (Box 159, Folder 8)
      Two issues. Began at Galileo High as an AAW project, later expanded to include Mission and George Washington. Second issue includes punk rock photo collage by Karen Wong, "courtesy CREEP magazine."
    - In Small Dreams (Opportunity II HS Creative Writing), 1978 (Box 159, Folder 9)
    - California Poets in the Schools anthologies, 1981-1987 (Box 159, Folder 10)
      "Could Sweet Taste Change Us" Edison 1981; "My Eyes Are All Out of Breath" California 1981; "Where the Hawks Hide" John Swett 1983; "I Hear The Sounds" Alvarado School 1987.
    - The Giant And the Clever Children (Alvarado After School Art Class, Nancy Thompson), 1989 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Ewald Foundation, 1994-1995 (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - MYEEP MegaZine Vol.3 No.1, 1998-1999 (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - Estudiantes de Una Gran Clase/ Students From a Great Class (Alvarado School), 2001 (Box 160, Folder 4)
      With portraits by Asawa.
    - miscellaneous publications (non-Bay Area) (Box 160, Folder 5)
  - 12.7 letters and artwork from students
    - undated (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - 2000-2009 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - guestbooks, 1988-2002 (Box 162, Folder 2)
      studio registry 1988-1991; open studio 1991; field trip to 1116 Castro 2000; "Completing the Circle" comment book, Oakland Museum 2002.
    - two bound items [unfoldered] (Box 126)
      Photo collages and poetry honoring Ruth’s art teaching workshops (Mission High, early 1970s); Courthouse Square Fountain Project (Santa Rosa, Burbank School 2/7/87, see also commission file).
  - 12.8 poster from Mission High School Graphics Department "Thank You Both - Ruth Asawa, Charlie Fowlie", 1973-06-06 (Flat-box 78, Folder 11)
  - 12.9 MADDS (Music Art Drama Dance Science) / Youth Arts Festival, 1969-2006
    Annual festival of children's art and performance in San Francisco. The first was organized by the Neighborhood Arts Program in 1973, but various groups have sponsored it since under different names.
    - 1969-1988 (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - 1989-2006 (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - slides - MADDS festival 1973-1975, Youth Arts Festival 1978, Event of the Year 1986 (Box 222, Folder 4)
    - photographs - Youth Arts Festival, MADDS 1975, Hooray For Kids Festival 1977 (Box 227, Folder 2)
    - Youth Arts Festival, SOTA event posters (Flat-box 193, Folder 3)
    - Images of the Youth Arts Festival 2006; DVD Movie; A Short Documentary of Student Visual Art as People View It [video], 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Produced program on 1986 Youth Arts Festival at de Young Museum. Asawa, Aiko Cuneo present.
    - S.F. Youth Arts Festival Gala Evening at the De Young [video], 2006-06-09; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 49, Folder 4)
      informally produced program on Youth Arts Festival 1986 gala at de Young Museum. Music by SOTA Orchestra, speeches, awards ceremony. Asawa, Paul Lanier present
- Series 13. Black Mountain College
  See also Ruth Asawa's Black Mountain College applications, records, and class notes under Juvenalia/School. Some alumni and faculty are filed in artist correspondence.
  Milwaukee State Teachers College Art Education teacher Howard Thomas had attended Black Mountain College's Summer Art Institute in 1944 with several students including Asawa's friends Hazel-Frieda Larsen and Elizabeth Schmitt. The following summer two other friends, Elaine Schmitt (Elizabeth's sister) and Ray Johnson signed up for the Art Institute. Asawa also applied, but decided to go study in Mexico instead.
  Meanwhile, after three years of MSTC, Asawa could not complete her degree without student teaching, but was told by her counselor that due to lingering anti-Japanese sentiment finding an internship in the area would be difficult. Based in part on her friends' recommendations, she decided to officially enroll at Black Mountain to study painting. Ruth spent nearly three years at BMC, from the summer of 1946 to June 1949, with two breaks: a second trip to Mexico in the Summer 1947 and to see her family in California the summer of 1948. Tuition was always hard to manage, and she relied on scholarships and extra work-study (including cutting hair, laundering, and making butter) to attend. A popular student, she was even voted student moderator her last semester.
  At the time, Black Mountain's pioneering educational experiment was hitting a post-war stride, and between the special summer sessions and regular semesters, Ruth was able to study with many of the school's greatest teachers. She repeatedly took Albers' Design and Color classes, and was a favorite student of his. She enrolled in Buckminster Fuller's Architecture and Industrial Design class and took math and philosophy with Max Dehn, music with Charlotte Schlesinger, English with M.C. Richards, and dance with Elizabeth Schmitt Jennerjahn and Merce Cunningham.
  Since there were no grades, it was also easy to sit in lectures by Jean Varda, Jacob Lawrence, Charles Olson, Beaumont Newhall, Leo Amino, and others. Ilya Bolotowsky, who taught art during one of the Albers' sabbaticals, described Asawa as "an excellent draftsman. In a style all her own, she combines modern realism with the Japanese elegance of line drawing." See the Juvenalia/School series for her class notes.
  Classmates included Robert Rauschenberg (with whom she danced in Rites of Spring), Arthur Penn (who directed Ruse of Medusa, for which Ruth made props), Joseph Fiore, Kenneth Noland, and Kenneth Snelson, but contrary to Black Mountain's reputation many alumni did not pursue careers in the arts. Of course this is also where she met Albert Lanier, who had come from Georgia to study architecture and design. Ruth and Albert were engaged at the school and from there moved to San Francisco, where there was a growing community of former students and teachers.
  Ruth and Albert first met Marguerite Wildenhain when she came to the College recruiting artists for the Pond Farm Workshops in Northern California. Textile artist and designer Trude Guermonprez, who was the Jalowetz' daughter, would later teach at Pond Farm after resigning from Black Mountain. Although there is almost no correspondence from them here, Guermonprez and her mother Johanna Jalowetz were among the closest of former BMCers in San Francisco.
  Correspondence includes letters from Mary Phelan Outten Bowles, the Dreier family, Mary Jo Slick Godfrey, Lorna Blaine Halper, Pete and Elizabeth Schmitt Jennerjahn, Frank Eisenrath, Toni and Max Dehn, Willie Joseph, Merv Lane, Charlotte "Bimbus" Schlesinger, Piet and Johanne Swierstra, Mary Parks Washington and many others. Original chronological order was retained.
  The artist correspondence series also contains files on alumni and teachers such as the Albers, the Fullers, and Ray Johnson, as well as Elaine Schmitt Urbain, Peggy Tolk-Watkins, Eva Heinitz, Raymond Barnhart, Remy Charlip, Marguerite Wildenhain, Andy Oates, Lisa Jalowetz Aronson, Kate and John Swackhamer, Allan Brooks, Ragland "Rags" Watkins, and Sewell Sillman.
  A great deal of the material here concerns various reunions and conferences about Black Mountain. Ruth was one of primary organizers for the large 1992 de Young reunion/symposium, and hosted multiple parties at her house. There are many files for this reunion, including audiovisual documentation. Some reunion participants are not otherwise represented in the correspondence section. Likewise, there is material in the reunion section from people who were not able to attend.
  Black Mountain College (Black Mountain, N.C.)
  - 13.1 correspondence with alumni and faculty
    - undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Includes a late 1940s letter from Lorna Halper with an Asawa drawing on the back.
    - 1949-1953 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Includes a letter to Asawa from her mother (in Japanese, see below for translation) 1/49; Paul Williams to the Laniers re: Minimum House article 2/50; Max and Toni Dehn to Asawa 11/24/51 with response by Ruth; and Mervin Lane to Asawa 7/52.
      translation of Haru Asawa letter by Mieko Mazza
      Happy New Year. How are you, Aiko-san? Please be assured that we are healthy and working. Thank you very much for sending us various things. THANK YOU VERY MUCH. Shirts, skirts, blouse and walnuts, quite a few gifts you sent us. Did you stay in college during your Christmas break? I expect you are having cold weather over there, too. Here in California, we are also having very cold weather. We have frost falling every day. How did you enjoy your New Year's holidays? Please take care of yourself as it is cold, and keep up the good work with your study. Are you going to have a school break on February? Masako-san wrote to us and told us she will visit us in June. January 3rd, Norwalk From mother to Aiko-sama
      Happy New Year. How are you, Aiko-san? Please be assured that we are healthy and working.
      Thank you very much for sending us various things. THANK YOU VERY MUCH. Shirts, skirts, blouse and walnuts, quite a few gifts you sent us. Did you stay in college during your Christmas break? I expect you are having cold weather over there, too. Here in California, we are also having very cold weather. We have frost falling every day. How did you enjoy your New Year's holidays?
      Please take care of yourself as it is cold, and keep up the good work with your study. Are you going to have a school break on February? Masako-san wrote to us and told us she will visit us in June.
      January 3rd, Norwalk
      From mother to Aiko-sama
    - 1954-1958 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1961-1964 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - 1977-1980 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - re: Bard College, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - re: de Young reunion and symposium, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folders 5-6)
    - 1993 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 1996 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 1999 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - 2002-2004 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - 2005-2013 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 13.2 Mary Emma Harris
    Harris, Mary Emma
    - correspondence (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - CD-Rs from Mary Emma Harris (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Data discs containing documents and images for the de Young retrospective.
  - 13.3 Asawa-Lanier art loans, etc. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 13.4 BMC Museum and Arts Center
    - correspondence, 1992-2013 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Black Mountain College Museum + Arts Center
    - publications (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Newsletters, exhibition cards and catalogs.
  - 13.5 Asheville Art Museum (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 13.6 1970 reunion, 1970-05-12 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Inspired by the publication of the Duberman book on BMC, Larry Fox organized a small reunion at a Jesuit monastery in Lenox, Massachusetts. Contains notes from Elaine Schmitt Urbain.
  - 13.7 1987 Bard College exhibition/symposium (Box 24, Folders 3-4)
  - 13.8 Tampa Museum of Art exhibition, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 13.9 1992 de Young reunion
    - planning, 1990-1991 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - fundraising and budget (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - SFSU course credit (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - documentation (videographer, etc.) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - logistics (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Merce Cunningham Foundation (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - list of slides for presentation (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - research notes (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - lists, addresses (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - speaker correspondence and biographies (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - flier, program, drafts (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - flier distribution (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - media (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - attendee addresses for distribution (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - group photo identification (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - transcript and video distribution, with release forms (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - questionaires A-Z (Box 22, Folders 3-4)
    - regrets (Box 22, Folders 5-6)
    - statements (Box 23, Folders 1-7)
    - statements and transcripts (as distributed) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - de Young Reunion guest book, March 6-8, 1992 (oversize), 1992-03 (Box 39)
  - 13.10 1992 de Young reunion A/V
    - "Return to Black Mountain" by Aiko Cuneo and Sally Young, 1992-03; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 51, Folder 12)
      Black Mountain alumni reunion. Party at 1116 Castro, group photo outside. A few shots from de Young event. Starring Sophia & Henry & [illeg.]. Edited By Fred [illeg.]. Video By: Sally Young.
    - BMC Reunion, 1992-03; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 52, Folder 3)
      Black Mountain College reunion event at de Young Museum. See other videos, audio.
    - BM Reunion. Ruth's Reception. Tape 1, 1992-03-08; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 52, Folder 4)
      By Sally Young. Black Mountain College reunion party at 1116 Castro. Tape log enclosed.
    - BM Reunion at the De Young and the Legion of Honor. Tape 1/ Tape 2, 1992-03; 2 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 52, Folder 5)
      By Sally Young. Black Mountain College reunion event at de Young Museum. 1. Different recording of second half of remarks and panel (lesser quality) 2. de Young event continued; [12:53] shots of 1116 Castro and neighborhood; [16:18] second part of Concert of Music and Dance, California Palace of the Legion of Honor. Remy Charlip dance performance followed by music composed Lou Harrison (present at end). Tape log enclosed.
    - BMC. Camerini Inc. Manvel Schauffler Interview at Ruth Asawa's House #1; Schauffler & Bonge. Ruth Asawa's House #2; Bonge Interview to 5 min. 20 sec. Party Shots. Ruth Asawa's House #3; Oberlander & Various Outtakes. Party Shots, Group Picture. Ruth Asawa's House. CH1 transmitted; CH2 on wire #4; Ruth Asawa's House. Group Picture, Conversation Bites #5; Mervin Lane, Ruth Asawa's House #6; Mervin Lane interview Cont'd. Ruth Asawa interview. Ruth Asawa's House #7; Ruth Asawa interview cont'd. Ruth Asawa Home #8, 1992-03-08; 8 videotape(s) (digital betacam) (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Formal interviews with and conversation among Black Mountain College reunion participants at 1116 Castro. Some footage from party, group photo.
    - BMC Reunion 3/6-8/1992. Master I-V, 1992-03; 5 audiocassette(s) (Box 54, Folder 1)
      Black Mountain College Reunion, de Young Museum, Trustee's Auditorium. Tape 1: Asawa introduction (also introduces each speaker); John Swackhamer (slides); Elizabeth Jennerjahn (slides, short silent film); Fielding Dawson -- Dawson cont.; M.C. Richards. Tape 2: Richards cont.; Asawa closing remarks, museum announcement; Joan Peterson; Page Smith -- Merv Lane; Manvel Schauffler; Eve Milton; Morton Steinau; Sue Spaeth Riley; Barbara Steinau; Lucian Marquis. Tape 3: Marquis cont.; Claude Stoller; Robert Bliss; Vera Williams; Patsy Lynch Woods; Judd Woldin; Larry Fox; Pete Jennerjahn; Elaine Urbain; Knute Stiles; Peter Oberlander. Tape 4: Lyle Bonge; Mary Bowles; Mary Parks Washington; Stanley Cooke; Dick Spahn; John Corkran -- Eva Jungermann; Fielding Dawson; Stephen De Staebler; break; Hannelore Hahn; Ruth Asawa, Mark Phillips, Joan Abrahamson (panel, Lois Gordon, moderator). Tape 5: panel cont.
    - Elaine, Rupert, Schmitt Family 3/92; Elizabeth Jennerjohn, Larry Fox, 1992-03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 54, Folder 2)
      Black Mountain College Reunion, informal gatherings. Side A: multiple conversations simultaneously, probably at 1116 Castro. Silence 15:50-26:43. different location, buffet, music. Side B: back at home, less overlapping talk. [17:00] discussion of Ruth's childhood.
    - Betty Jennerjahn. 1116 Castro, 1992-03-09; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 54, Folder 3)
      Asawa, Jennerjahn and male speaker (Pete and or Albert?) re: reunion, Fiore, homosexuality, Duberman, Dawson, Eisendrath, etc.
    - Pete [Jennerjahn]. BM, 1992-03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 54, Folder 4)
      Elaine Urbain, Pete Jennerjahn, Rupert Schmitt, Albert Lanier, Ruth Asawa in casual conversation, probably at 1116 Castro
    - BMC Reunion. Lou Harrison, Legion of Honor, 1992-03-07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Ruth's recording. Concert of Music and Dance, Florence Gould Theater, California Palace of the Legion of Honor. Side A: John Cage program. "Nocturne" (1947). David Abel, violin and Julie Steinberg, piano; "Music For Two" (1984). Barbara Chaffe, flute and William Winant, percussion; "Aria" (1958). Judith Bettina, sporano; Remy Charlip "Five Dances and Four Songs in One Place"; Lou Harrison program. "May Rain" (1941). Judith Bettina, soprano; "Air for Solo Flute" (1947). Barbara Chaffe, flute; "Songs in the Forest" (1951, edited 1992, premiere). Barbara Chaffe, flute, David Abel, violin, Julie Steinberg, piano, William Winant, percussion, Lou Harrison, narration; "Varied Trio" (1987). Abel-Steinberg-Winant Trio
  - 13.11 1993 reunion honoring Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - 13.12 1995 reunion (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - 13.13 interview transcripts
    See also Asawa statements series
    - Lanier and Asawa, "Summer of 48" draft of book chapter with edits, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Lanier and Asawa interview for Duberman book, 1968-06-28 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Lanier, Asawa, Outtens interviews by Mary Emma Harris, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Ted Drier interview, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      Dreier, Theodore
    - Asawa College of Arts and Crafts lecture, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Asawa statement, 1978-07 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Asawa public television, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Asawa interview by Mary Emma Harris, 1998-02-17 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Asawa interview by Aiko Cuneo re: BMC art, 2003-12-05 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Harris and Cuneo working notes for BMC portion of "Contours" book/exhibition (Box 35, Folders 10-11)
  - 13.14 miscellaneous publications (exhibitions, symposia, etc.) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 13.15 BMC articles (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 13.16 new Black Mountain College, 1989-1991 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 13.17 Jonathan Williams, Jargon Society, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Jargon Society
  - 13.18 photocopies
    - Mary Parks Washington – Albers class notes, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Washington, Mary Parks; Albers, Josef
    - Elaine Schmitt correspondence home, 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - photographs from Clemens Kalischer; song lyrics (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Kalischer, Clemens
    - student petition [original] (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Petition to Board re: accepting Charles Olson as summer faculty. Signed by several students, but not Asawa.
  - 13.19 photographs
    - miscellaneous alumni and faculty (Box 217, Folder 1)
      Charlotte "Bimbus" Schlesinger, Ted Dreier and Drier Family, Piet and Johannes Swierstra, Peter Oberlander and Eva Heinitz 1993, Wes Huss 1998, Max Dehn's grave at BMC (photographed 1956), Robert Rauschenberg in San Francisco 1992, etc.
    - Albert Lanier and Johanna Jalowetz, 1949 (Box 217, Folder 2)
      Copy of old print with new negative. With other BMC and family negatives.
    - Ruth Asawa in Elizabeth Schmitt Jennerjahn dance class, 1948 (Box 217, Folder 3)
      Photographs probably by Jennerjahn. Seven original prints cut from scrapbook with new prints and negatives.
    - portrait of Asawa by Hazel-Frieda Larsen Archer (Box 217, Folder 4)
      Mounted on cardboard.
      Archer, Hazel Larsen
    - portraits of Asawa by Hazel-Frieda Larsen Archer (Box 217, Folder 5)
      Four vintage prints with new negatives.
    - miscellaneous BMC photographs (photocopies) (Box 217, Folder 6)
      Sent by Frank Eisenrath, who originally took them.
    - copy of 1995 letter from Renee Siegel Collins with new print of Eisenrath photo and 3 slides (Box 217, Folder 7)
    - copy of 2009 Ted Dreier Jr. letter with photocopy of Ruth and Albert photograph (now in NC State Archive) (Box 217, Folder 8)
    - photos of Asawa and San Miguel Mission by Hazel-Frieda Larsen Archer, 1957 (Box 217, Folder 9)
      Sent to Ruth c/o Kneedler-Fauchere (they sold her industrial designs for wall coverings).
    - BMC Reunion Bard College, 1987 (Box 217, Folder 10)
    - BMC Reunion San Francisco, 1992 (Box 217, Folders 11-12)
      Many snapshots of de Young and 1116 Castro events, including some with correspondence by Elaine Schmitt Urbain, the Jennerjahns, Frank Eisenrath. See also video.
    - BMC Reunion, group photo in front of 1116 Castro, 1992 (Box 217, Folder 13)
      Includes Aiko’s original negative.
    - BMC Reunions, etc., 1993 (Box 217, Folder 14)
      Lisa Aronson hosted small reunion in New York. Ruth and Albert hosted Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight at a small gathering at their house. Raymond Barnhart sent photos of his trip to Black Mountain in 1993.
    - BMC Reunion at Black Mountain, 1995 (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - Reunion of Alumni and Friends of Black Mountain College, by Benjamin Porter, 1995-10-28 (Map-folder 56)
      Group photograph in front of Lake Eden.
    - landscape photos, 2000, 2011 (Box 218, Folder 2)
- Series 14. Public Service
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, etc. from the various commissions, committees, councils, boards, task forces, and other groups Ruth Asawa participated in. See also the Activism and Advocacy series.
  - 14.1 California Arts Council, 1973-2003
    Following a reorganization of the California Arts Council in 1975, Asawa served on the Council, working especially with the Artists-in-the-Schools and Artist-in-Communities programs. Other members during her tenure included Gary Snyder, Peter Coyote, Luis Valdez, Noah Purifoy, and Allauddin Mathieu. She chose to leave in 1979.
    California Arts Council
    - 1973-1975 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Artists-In-Communities grant applications for review, 1975 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - 1976 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - CAC report, 1976 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Artists-in-the-Schools, 1976 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Alternatives in Education grant program (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - 1977 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - 1978 (Box 89, Folder 4)